#### **CURRICULUM VITAE**

PH: 0481840101 | EMAIL: raginimalhotra0904@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ragini-malhotra-336635117/ 20 Renouf Street Casey, ACT

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a hardworking and highly self-motivated individual completed my Master of Professional Engineering (Specializing in Software Engineering). I have strong communication, organization and teamwork skills that have been developed through my extensive work experience. I constantly strive to further improve my skills by taking advantage of every opportunity and produce excellence through careful attention to detail and passion in my work.

**EDUCATION** 

### **Master of Software Engineering**

**March 2016 – November 2017** 

University of Western Australia, Crawley, WA

WAM: 72.563

**Bachelor of Technology** (Electronics and Communication Engineering)

**August 2011 – May 2015** 

DAV Institute of Engineering and Technology

WAM: 81.23 (High Distinction)

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Vacation Work Experience**

**December 2016 – February 2017** 

Huon, Canberra, ACT

I worked within the quality assurance division, gaining valuable industry experience whilst supporting a large team. In this highly skilled team, I was responsible for a wide range of challenging tasks, including in-depth research on quality assurance of an online tool for the company. I was required to build an online tool for the company to maintain safety and quality of projects going on at construction sites. The experience allowed me to gain a better understanding of my personal career paths, and also assisted in the development of my professional skills.

# **Vacation Work Experience**

**June 2014 – November 2014** 

Quadrant Televentures, India

During my time at Quadrant Televentures, I was able to learn a great deal, not only about mobile site management but also about the professional services sector as a whole. I was challenged with real client work and had many responsibilities that I was held accountable for. I was engaged in a broad range of activities, from smaller administrative duties to forming a proposal for a client. I worked closely with field engineer and senior management to identify requirements and plan proposals.

**MAJOR PROJECTS** 

### **Design Project**

**March 2016 - November 2017** 

University of Western Australia, Perth

The ePortfolio is an online tool that allows students to maintain a portfolio of their practical experiences throughout the duration of their study. The ePortfolio has been created specifically for students undertaking the Master of Professional Engineering at the University of Western Australia who are required to demonstrate sixteen competencies specified by Engineers Australia.

### **Research Thesis**

**March 2016 – November 2017** 

University of Western Australia, Perth

In this project, I used deep neural network models to develop an end to end system that performs face detection, and expression recognition.

#### Sales Assistant

November 2016 - March 2017

Lagardere Travel Retail

As a sales assistant, I provided first-class customer service, have developed a loyal customer base of regular's shoppers, and constantly achieved outstanding sales results.

**Tutor** 

July 2016 - July 2017

Ezy Math Tutors, Grace Simpkins Personal Tutors

I was employed to commence tutoring for Mathematics and Physics. As a tutor, I hope to effectively communicate complex ideas to students in simple ways. I also hope to act as a mentor, offering guidance and motivation to my students.

#### **SKILLS**

Software: Extensive knowledge in C, C++, Core JAVA, python, MATLAB, Assembly programming 8085/8086,

HTML, Javascript, Angular JS, Continuous Integration, Cloud Computing

Platforms: Spyder, Netbeans, Turbo C, KEIL uVision IDE, NS3, Amazon Cloud Services

Operating systems: Windows, LINUX, OSX

Proficient in MS Office, Mac, Windows 98/2000/xp/vista/7 Operating systems

#### COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

### **Volunteer: Postgraduate Unimentor**

February 2016 – October 2017

Volunteered as mentor in the university of Western Australia. As a mentor, my responsibilities included providing mentees with accurate and relevant information about their faculty and provide mentees with maps and resources, directions to venues as well as key information about services and supports for new students.

#### **Society of Innovative Technocrackers**

2012-2015

Volunteered in the technical support crew for college productions, ensuring that performances ran smoothly.

### **Memberships**

UWA Student Guild, Student member Engineers Australia, Postgraduate member of National Tertiary Education Union (NTEU), University Engineer's Club, CSSC (Computer Science Students' Club)

# **AWARDS**

#### **International Master's by Coursework Scholarship**

2015

The University of Western Australia, Perth

Awarded scholarship of \$14000 by University of Western Australia on the basis of Academic achievement.

#### **Graduate Aptitude Test In Engineering (GATE)**

2015

Indian Institute of Technology, Kanpur

Qualified and scored 91.4 percentile in GATE examination

#### Merit Award 2014

DAV Institute of Engineering and Technology

Awarded for excellent achievement in academics

# TechnoShockers Award

2013

DAV Institute of Engineering and Technology

Awarded for excellence and participation on Engineer's Day

#### REFEREES

Available on request